[Music]
foreign
start with a triangle with sides of
length a b and c
the angle bisectors of this triangle
meet at a point
this point is known as the in center of
the triangle and it's also the center of
a circle known as The Inn circle of the
triangle which is a circle that is
tangent to all three sides and the
largest Circle that fits inside the
triangle if we draw the radii that are
perpendicular to each of the sides we
get a shape that looks like this and we
can fill the six regions with different
colored triangles
now let's unfold these triangular
regions so that they all lay out in a
line of triangles like this with bases
that are all parallel
if we take a second copy of this shape
flip it upside down and then shift the
triangles as we see here we end up with
a nice rectangular shape
in fact we can find the dimensions of
this rectangle using the original labels
of the triangle
as shown in the picture
we see that the length of the rectangle
is a plus b plus C while the width of
the rectangle is the in radius length R
but now we see a nice fact 2 times the
area of the original triangle must be
equal to R the length of the in radius
times a plus b plus C the length of the
perimeter but this means that the area
of the triangle is equal to R times a
plus b plus C over 2 which is R times s
where s is known as the semiperimeter so
we've proved that the area of a triangle
is the product of the radius in the
semiperimeter